GUY CHERKESKY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

(615) 870-7537
cherkesky.com
guy@cherkesky.com
linkedin.com/in/cherkesky
github.com/cherkesky

ABOUT ME

I always wanted to be a software developer. When I was 13 years old in Tel Aviv, I taught myself Basic and Logo programming languages out of books and fell in love with coding. The endless possibilities that can only be limited by one's own creativity sparked my imagination. I moved to the US in 2011 and opened my own business. I put coding aside for a while and continued pursuing other entrepreneurship endeavors but never gave up on my dream to be a professional software developer. When I heard about Nashville Software School I saw my opportunity to start this new career, and I went for it. Now I can't imagine anything else I would rather do.

CAPSTONE PROJECTS

CHASER - github.com/cherkesky/Chaser

Chaser is an in-bar drink sending app built using React.js. It grabs your geolocation and allows you to 'check-in' to a bar in your proximity. Once checked-in, user is able to see others who are checked in as well. Drink requests can be sent as well as received. Approving a drink request will open a limited chat with 3 messages per user for basic communication, eg, 'where are you sitting', 'what do you want to drink?' The chat will destruct when complete. Users are placed in a 30 minute 'time out' to allow them to get to know each other without being distracted by other users.

 Also utilizes, JavaScript, Material-UI, CSS, Real Time GeoLocation, Google Places API, Google Maps API, Cloudinary API, JSON Server, Alertify.js, Figma.

GENIE.IO - github.com/cherkesky/GenielO

Genie.IO is a Full Stack React.js/Django app that connects users who want to make a wish (ex: I want to pass calculus) to users that think they can grant their wishes (ex: I'm a calculus instructor. I think I can help you!). There is a dedicated section for the Wishers to send their wishes and a section for Granters to search for a wish to grant. If a Wisher gets a Grant request they can reject or approve the request. If they choose to approve the request, their contact info will be shared with the Granter. The home page shows a word cloud made from the wish's keywords. The wishes are processed with NLTK to remove all the stop words and leave only the important keywords for the word cloud. Genie.IO also allows users to text wishes from their phones

 Also utilizes JavaScript, Python, Material-UI, CSS, Node.js, Express, Mongo.DB, SQLite3, Twilio, Figma.

TECH EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | Sep 2019 - PRESENT

- Intensive full-time, six-month web development bootcamp that focuses on the skills and technologies required to become a full-stack software developer.
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub and project managing/tracking with Github Projects
- JavaScript fundamentals using DRY, modular, readable code and reusable components
- Experience using Bootstrap, Material UI, and CSS to style web applications
- Experience building single page applications with React.js
- Hands on application of Object Oriented Programming fundamentals
- Leveraged Django to create server-side Python web applications
- Experience utilizing raw SQL queries to interact with the database
- Comfortable with group and individual projects reflecting real-world team dynamics and problem solving
- Self taught: FreePBX, Node.JS, Express, Wordpress, Google Analytics

GROUP PROJECTS

Bangazon - Full Stack React/Django based online retail app https://github.com/cherkesky/bangazon

Kewlyrics - Javascript based lyrics search engine github.com/cherkesky/KewLyrics-NSS-Hackathon

Nutshell - React.JS based social network github.com/cherkesky/reactive-nutshell

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

555 LEADS AND SERVICES, OWNER

2012-2018

Provided on-line advertising, a 24/7 call center, and lead generation services to independent contractors across the nation.

- Established a call center and on-line lead generation business from scratch
- Negotiating contracts with various service providers and effectively planned, budgeted and executed on business network initiatives
- Successfully adapted to constant changes, needs, budgets while triaging problems and identifying short and long-term solutions
- Generated leads for the business clients
- Produced and reviewed periodic reports
- Oversaw processing of all payroll and bonuses using QuickBooks
- Assessed business performance through established, well defined Key Performance Indicators (KPI)
- Defined, customized, ran, and maintained an open-source FreePBX phone server
- Partnered with local entrepreneurs in Mexico and the Philippines to create high functioning off-shore team
- Led recruitment and training of customer service representatives and supervisors
- Managed a diverse team including 30 local employees and 50 off-shore employees

COMVERSE

QA ACTIVITY LEAD | Jun 2010 - May 2011

Comverse develops and markets value-added telecommunication software for mobile network carriers.

- Created Software Testing Documents (STD) according to Marketing/R&D requirements and effectively prioritized based on project timelines
- Responsible for a team of 3, including day to day management and work delegation
- Upgraded tests and modifications to current software versions
- Testing Execution (End-2-End, System components) performed according to specifications
- Test planning and execution while enforcing the QA methodology
- Supported other QA teams in similar testing areas
- Executed all tests in Linux/Unix environment and documented in Quality Center (Mercury)

QUALITEST

QA SUPERVISOR | Jul 2007 - Jun 2010

Qualitest is an international software testing company.

- Promoted to supervisor from role of Manual Tester in first 6 months
- Point of contact for Qualitest's clients
- Established work guidelines and methodologies for Qualitest's clients
- Recruited, led, and mentored a team of three QA people (2 manual testers and 1 automated)
- Designed, implemented and executed manual tests including regression, sanity and functional testing. GUI, unit tests, DB, localization and integration testings.
- Wrote and documented Software Test Documents (STD), Software Test Plans (STP) & Software Test Report files (STR) and project management in MS-Project, producing gantt reports
- Met deadlines while widening QualiTest's business activities in the client's project

MILITARY EXPERIENCE - IDF ISRAEL DEFENSE FORCES

1998 - 2011

LIEUTENANT IN RESERVE | Jan 2002 - May 2007

- Configured and operated proprietary Electronic Warfare technology
- · Represented the unit in cross-branch meetings
- Managed 1-3 soldiers during irregular hours and conditions

ELECTRONIC WARFARE OFFICER | Sep 1999 - Dec 2002

- Served in a staff position of Electronic Warfare (EW) operation officer. During that time, I took on an additional challenge and fulfilled the unit's computer network needs
- Filled an educational position as the Electronic Warfare course commander
- · Managed 5 soldiers during irregular hours and conditions

ELECTRONIC WARFARE TECHNICIAN | Dec 1998 - Sep 1999

 Served as a trained Electronic Warfare soldier. The position included configuring and operating advanced proprietary technology

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School, Full-stack Developer Bootcamp (2019 - present)

The Open University Of Israel, Computer Sciences & Business Administration (2007 - 2011)

Brightwood College, Electrical Technician Certification (2015)

COMMUNITY

- · Code For Nashville Volunteer (2019 present)
- · TN Courts Hebrew/English Interpreter (2015 present)